Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we've got another lesson in our series about small talk today.
我是Catherine，今天我们系列课程中又有一节关于闲聊的课。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are at the office again and we're going to be talking very briefly about something,
今天我们再次来到办公室，我们将简短地谈论一些事情，
a business meeting that we're going to have soon.
一个我们即将召开的商务会议。
That's right.
没错。
So let's check out our dialogue.
那么让我们来看看对话。
We'll be back in a moment.
我们一会儿回来。
I'm Michelle.
我是Michelle。
Hi, I was hoping to see you.
嗨，我正希望能见到你。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
How's the family?
家人还好吗？
Oh, hello, Mr. Campbell.
哦，你好，Campbell先生。
I'm fine and Jack's doing well.
我很好，Jack也很好。
How are you?
你好吗？
I'm fine.
我很好。
Thanks.
谢谢。
I got your report this morning.
我今天早上收到了你的报告。
Thanks for that.
谢谢。
Are you joining the conference today?
你今天要参加那个会议吗？
Yes, I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
是的，我下午四点出发。
Good.
好的。
Well, we can discuss this more then.
嗯，那我们到时候再详细讨论。
But I think the figures are looking very good for this quarter.
但我认为这个季度的数据看起来很不错。
Yes, me too.
是的，我也这么觉得。
I'm planning to discuss the advertising budget at the conference.
我计划在会议上讨论广告预算。
I don't think we should continue with the TV advertising.
我认为我们不应该继续做电视广告了。
No, me neither. It's far too expensive.
不，我也这么觉得。那太贵了。
Well, let's discuss this more at the conference. Maybe we can share a taxi there?
嗯，我们会议上再详细讨论吧。也许我们可以一起打车去那里？
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然。
All right, we're back, so now let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Today in Language Takeaway we have a number of phrases and words about business. The first
今天的“语言要点”中，我们有一些关于商务的短语和词汇。第一个
one we have is, are you joining the conference today?
是，“你今天要参加那个会议吗？”
That's right. So we're going to go to a conference, actually, which is a little bit different
没错。所以我们要去参加一个会议，实际上，这和
than a meeting.
会议有点不同。
That's right. A meeting is something you normally do with people at your own company. But a
没错。会议通常是你和自己公司的人进行的。但
conference is when people from many different companies meet.
会议是来自不同公司的人聚在一起。
That's right. And also, I think you don't really have too much input at a conference.
没错。而且，我觉得在会议上你通常不会有太多发言权。
You mostly listen to other people speak about a topic or a subject.
你主要是听别人谈论某个话题或主题。
That's right. And I think these are normally held in conference centers or hotels. You
没错。而且我认为这些通常是在会议中心或酒店举行的。你
have a nice lunch. So they're pretty big deals.
会吃一顿不错的午餐。所以这是挺大的活动。
That's right. All right, so it's more of a formal business conference that we're going
没错。好的，所以我们要去的是一个更正式的商务会议。而且，
to. And well, they're actually going to discuss different aspects of the company as well,
他们实际上也会讨论公司的不同方面，
especially the figures.
尤其是数据。
All right. So in the context of business, the word figure actually means number. Okay,
好的。所以在商务语境中，“figure”这个词实际上指的是数字。好吧，
so we can say the sales numbers for this year are a kind of figure.
我们可以说今年的销售数字就是一种数据。
That's right. So we're talking about money, basically, when we're talking about numbers.
没错。所以当我们谈论数字时，基本上是在谈论钱。
That's right. So when the figures look good, it means that our income, our revenue, this
没错。所以当数据看起来不错时，意味着我们的收入、我们的营收，
looks good.
看起来不错。
That's right. And when we usually talk about income or revenue, we usually have to separate
没错。当我们谈论收入或营收时，通常需要按时间
it into time. And here in the dialogue, we're talking about a quarter.
划分。在对话中，我们谈到了一个季度。
All right, so quarter, Q-U, quarter, is a period of time, very common in business, that
好的，所以“quarter”，Q-U，quarter，是一个时间段，在商务中很常见，
is a quarter of the year. So three months.
是一年的四分之一。也就是三个月。
Three months, that's right.
三个月，没错。
January, February, March, April, May, June, and so on.
一月、二月、三月，四月、五月、六月，等等。
That's right. So you have four quarters. And that's actually what, that's why you call
没错。所以你有四个季度。实际上，这就是为什么你叫它
it a quarter because it's one fourth.
quarter，因为它是四分之一。
So we can say the figures for the first quarter were very good, but unfortunately, the figures
所以我们可以说第一季度的数据非常好，但不幸的是，
for the second quarter were very bad.
第二季度的数据非常糟糕。
That's right. And actually, another similar way that you use quarter is the 25 cent coin.
没错。实际上，另一个类似使用“quarter”的方式是25美分硬币。
It's called a quarter because it's a quarter of a dollar.
它被称为quarter，因为它是四分之一美元。
That's right. And if you're in America, you know that it has an eagle, a bird on one side
没错。如果你在美国，你知道它一面有一只鹰，一只鸟。
of it.
没错。
That's right. All right, so we are taking a look at the figures for the quarter. And
好的，所以我们正在查看这个季度的数据。而且
they're saying, well, it's not looking too good because we need to talk about the advertising
他们说，嗯，看起来不太好，因为我们需要讨论广告
budget.
预算。
All right. So this is something that you think is very important. It's budget. It's how much
好的。所以这是你认为非常重要的事情。这是预算。这是你
money you have to spend on something. And in this case, you're spending it on advertising.
在某件事上可以花的钱。在这种情况下，你把它花在广告上。
So this is ads that you make.
也就是你制作的广告。
That's right. So as you said, a budget is the amount of money that you have available
没错。正如你所说，预算是你可用的
to spend on something. And on this occasion, we're talking about advertising. Now, you
用于某件事的金额。这次我们在谈论广告。现在，你
can have a budget for different things, right?
可以为不同的事情制定预算，对吧？
You could have a marketing budget.
你可以有营销预算。
So the money you have for marketing.
也就是你用于营销的钱。
You could have a personnel budget, which is the money you would set aside for people.
你可以有人事预算，这是你为员工预留的钱。
So how much you pay your employees. Right. So you can pretty much mix up many different
也就是你付给员工的工资。对。所以你可以把很多不同的
nouns with budget. Even you can have a budget for your home. How much you spend at home.
名词和预算搭配起来。甚至你可以在家里有预算。你在家里花多少钱。
That's right. So many people have this for their families. They say this month I will
没错。所以很多人为他们的家庭这样做。他们说这个月我会
spend $100 on shopping and $200 on shoes.
花100美元购物，200美元买鞋。
So it's like a family budget, you would call it.
所以这就像你所说的家庭预算。
That's right. Okay. So that's all the words we have for you on language takeaway. Let's
没错。好的。这就是我们在语言摘录部分为你准备的所有单词。让我们
review everything quickly and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
快速复习一下，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
Ah, Michelle. Hi. I was hoping to see you. How have you been? How's the family?
啊，米歇尔。嗨。我正希望见到你。你最近怎么样？家人还好吗？
Oh, hello, Mr. Campbell. I'm fine and Jack's doing well. How are you?
哦，你好，坎贝尔先生。我很好，杰克也不错。你呢？
I'm fine. Thanks. I got your report this morning. Thanks for that. Are you joining the conference
我很好。谢谢。我今天早上收到了你的报告。谢谢。你要参加今天的会议吗？
today?
今天？
Yes, I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
是的，我下午4点出发。
Good. Well, we can discuss this more then. But I think the figures are looking very good
好的。那我们到时候再详细讨论。不过我觉得这个季度的数字看起来很不错。
for this quarter.
这个季度。
Yes, me too.
是的，我也这么觉得。
I'm planning to discuss the advertising budget at the conference. I don't think we should
我计划在会议上讨论广告预算。我认为我们不应该
continue with the TV advertising.
继续做电视广告。
No, me neither. It's far too expensive.
不，我也不这么认为。那太贵了。
Well, let's discuss this more at the conference. Maybe we can share a taxi there.
好的，那我们会议上再详细讨论。也许我们可以一起打车去那里。
Yes, sir.
好的，先生。
Alright, in today's Fluency Builder, we have a number of phrases you could use in a small
好的，在今天的流利度训练中，我们有一些短语可以在闲聊场合使用。第一个是问题：家人还好吗？
talk situation. The first one's a question. How's the family?
家人还好吗？注意，这是“how's the family”，对吧？所以是“how is the family”。
How's the family? Now, it's how apostrophe s the family, right? So how is the family
would be the extended way of saying it.
这就是更完整的说法。
That's right. But this is a short way to say it. It's very common. And you normally say
没错。但这是简略的说法，很常见。通常你会说
this with people who are a little bit older, people who have kids. So I haven't seen you
和那些年纪稍大、有孩子的人一起。所以我一直没见到你。
in a long time, Marco, and I know you have some kids and I can say, how's the family?
好久不见，Marco。我知道你有孩子了，我想问一下，家里人都好吗？
How's the family? That's right. And it's actually, it may seem strange the way that this sentence
How's the family? 家人怎么样？That's right. 没错。And it's actually, it may seem strange the way that this sentence 而且实际上，这个句子的表达方式可能看起来有点奇怪。
is made, but it's very, very much similar to how are you? You have how to be and you
是的，但它和“how are you”非常非常相似。你有“how to be”和“you”。
in the subject.
在主题里。
That's right. And this is a very polite way to say hi. How are you? How is your family?
没错。这是一种非常礼貌的打招呼方式。你好吗？你的家人怎么样？
How is the wife?
你妻子怎么样了？
How's the wife? And she said, well, you know what? Everything is great. I'm fine. And Jack's,
妻子怎么样？然后她说，你知道吗？一切都很好。我挺好的。杰克呢？
I guess that's her husband, is doing well.
我猜那是她丈夫，他过得不错。
Jack is doing well. So doing well, thanks. This means good. Okay. But you know, when
Jack is doing well. 杰克过得不错。
So doing well, thanks. 所以，过得不错，谢谢。
This means good. 这表示“好”。
Okay. 好的。
But you know, when 但你知道，当……
we say the answer to this question, how are you? I'm well. That's the correct answer.
我们回答这个问题“你好吗？”时，应该说“我很好”。这才是正确的答案。
I'm good is not correct.
“I'm good”这种说法是不正确的。
Right. So if somebody says, how are you? You can say, I'm well. Or you can say, I'm doing
好的。所以如果有人问“你好吗？”，你可以回答“我很好。”或者你可以说“我过得不错。”
well.
嗯。
That's a positive answer. Things are going well. You could say, not so well. That's not
这是一个积极的回答。事情进展顺利。你也可以说，不太顺利。那不对。
a, not, not, not good things are happening.
啊，不，不，不好的事情正在发生。
Very good. And it's very important to point out the difference. As Catherine said, you
很好。而且指出其中的区别非常重要。正如Catherine所说，你
don't, you don't, you shouldn't use good. I'm doing good or I'm good.
不要，你不要，你不应该用“good”。比如“I'm doing good”或“I'm good”。
Yeah, no, it's incorrect because good is an adjective and we're, we're looking for an
对，不，这是不对的，因为 good 是形容词，而我们需要一个
adverb here.
副词。
That's right.
没错。
Well.
嗯。
That's correct. All right. And to finish things off, Mr. Campbell and Michelle were headed,
正确。好了，最后，坎贝尔先生和米歇尔朝着同一个方向走。
headed the same way. So they decided to share a taxi.
所以他们决定一起打一辆出租车。
That's right. So to share a taxi means two people or three people will pay for one taxi
没错。所以 share a taxi 意思是两个人或三个人一起付一辆出租车的钱。
together. So maybe Marco, I see you on the street and I know that you have to go to a
所以，马可，我在街上看到你，知道你要去参加一个
conference. I'm going to the same conference. Let's share a taxi. It will cost less.
会议。我也去同一个会议。我们拼车吧，这样更省钱。
That's right. So you will share the cost between all the people in the cab. Now there's another
没错。所以你们会分摊出租车里所有人的费用。现在还有另一种
way of saying it as well. More common, I think in the, in the United States.
说法。在美国，我觉得更常见。
That's right. We say split a taxi. Let's split a cab.
没错。我们说 split a taxi。Let's split a cab。
Split a cab. Now remember that it's a taxi cab. So sometimes people just don't say taxi.
Split a cab。记住，它是 taxi cab。所以有时人们直接不说 taxi。
They say a cab. Let's split a cab. Let's share a cab.
他们说 cab。Let's split a cab。Let's share a cab。
That's right. Cab, taxi, both are okay.
没错。Cab 和 taxi 都可以。
All right. Very good. Good stuff. Let's listen to everything one last time.
好了，非常好。内容不错。我们最后再听一遍。
Ah, Michelle. Hi. I was hoping to see you. How have you been? How's the family?
啊，米歇尔。嗨。我正希望见到你。你最近怎么样？家人好吗？
Oh, hello, Mr. Campbell. I'm fine and Jack's doing well. How are you?
哦，你好，坎贝尔先生。我很好，杰克也不错。你呢？
I'm fine. Thanks. I got your report this morning. Thanks for that. Are you joining the conference
我很好，谢谢。我今天早上收到了你的报告，谢谢。你今天要参加
today? Yes, I'm leaving at 4 p.m.
会议吗？是的，我下午四点出发。
Good. Well, we can discuss this more then. But I think the figures are looking very good
好的。那我们到时候再详细讨论。不过我觉得这些数字看起来很不错。
for this quarter. Yes, me too.
这个季度。是的，我也这么认为。
I'm planning to discuss the advertising budget at the conference. I don't think we should
我打算在会议上讨论广告预算。我觉得我们不应该
continue with the TV advertising. No, me neither. It's far too expensive.
继续做电视广告。不，我也不赞成。电视广告太贵了。
Well, let's discuss this more at the conference. Maybe we can share a taxi there?
好吧，那我们会议上再细聊。也许我们可以一起打车去那里？
Yes, sure. All right. So we're getting towards the end
好的，当然。好了，我们快接近尾声了
of our Small Talk series. As you can see, we are taking a look at different quick but
我们的闲聊系列。如你所见，我们正在看一些简短但
very useful dialogues that you can have with someone, a small conversation, whether about
非常实用的对话，你可以和别人进行简短交谈，无论是关于
business, family, whatever. That's right. And in today's dialogue, we
工作、家庭还是其他话题。没错。在今天的对话中，我们
heard two people who probably know each other talking. So sometimes you're with people who
听到了两个可能认识的人在交谈。所以有时候你遇到陌生人，
are strangers, you don't know what to say to them. You can listen to our other episodes
不知道跟他们说什么。你可以听我们其他关于闲聊的节目，
on Small Talk for things to talk about with those people.
了解跟那些人聊什么话题。
That's right. And of course, if you have any questions or comments, you can visit us at
没错。当然，如果你有任何问题或评论，可以访问我们的网站
EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you all there. Until next
EnglishPod.com。我们希望能在那里见到大家。下次见。
time. Bye.
再见。
Bye.